Finding Aid for Commercial catalog collection, 1870s-2000s
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Clothing and Dress
  - Port Huron Fibre Garment Mf'g Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Alaska fibre garments. 1896 (Box 8)
  - R. H. Fyfe and Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue of shoes for 1912-1913 (Box 8)
  - Rosenthal Co., Flint, Mich
    - Catalogue of Irene Castle Corticelli fashions circa 1925 (Box 8)
  - Schmidt, Henry L., Merchant Tailor, Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Folder announcing opening of the new season (Pocket with 6 plates showing men's fashions Fall-Winter 1922-1923 (Box 8)
  - Siegel's Men's Bazaar, Detroit, Mich
    - Home Talk, A Household Magazine January 1899 (Box 8)
  - Staebler and Wuerth, Ann Arbor, Mich
    - A fashion book for men, Autumn-Winter 1903-1904 [suits and overcoats] (Box 8)
  - Sullivan-Cook Co., Ypsilanti, Mich
    - Exclusive summer tailoring. 1903 (Box 8)
  - W. M. Bennett and Sons, Jackson, Mich
    - The journal of fashion. v. 1, no. 4 September 1875 (Box 8)
      (mutilated)
  - Weaver, W. W., Custom Fur Tanning and Manufacturer, Reading, Mich
    - 2 price lists for custom tanning. circa 1920 (Box 8)
    - Coat manufacturing and lining. circa 1920 (Box 8)
  - Whitney Scenic & Costume Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Costumes of quality Undated (Box 8)
- Magic Tricks--Equipment and Supplies (Box 9)
  - Abbott's Magic Novelty Co., Colon, Mich
    - Catalog no. 3 circa 1937 (Box 9)
    - Catalog no. 9 1947 (Box 9)
  - Johnson Smith & Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalog no. 148 1938 (Box 9)
- Department, Dry Goods, and Miscellaneous Stores (Box 10)
  - Bluff Gardens, Harbor Springs, Mich
    - [Catalog] Holiday 1999 (Box 10)
  - Bronner's Christmas Wonderland, Frankenmuth, Mich
    - Bronner's Christmas favorites. 1993-1994 (Box 10)
  - Hannah and Lay Merchandising Co., Traverse City, Mich
    - Catalogue of men and women's clothing, furniture, kitchen utensils, agricultural equipment Spring-Summer 1908 (Box 10)
  - Newcomb, Endicott and Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Gifts. Christmas 1923 (Box 10)
  - Richardi & Bechtold, Bellaire, Mich
    - Woodenware Undated, [kitchen and laundry utensils; with salesman's annotations] (Box 10)
  - Shaft, J. M., Shaftsburg, Mich
    - Factory price catalog for 1915 (Box 10)
      [stoves and ranges, refrigerators, washing machines, dairy supplies, sewing machines, building materials, portable forges, tools, guns, pumps, bicycles, gasoline engines, wind mills, galvanized steel ware, fences, farrier equipment, buggies and wagons, scales, saw mills, agricultural equipment, etc.]
- Drugs and Pharmaceuticals
  - Anderson Manufacturing Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue of pharmaceutical, apparatus, machinery, supplies, etc. [cat. no. 2, for 1890] (Box 10)
  - Higby and Stearns, Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue of prices--current of drugs, chemicals, pharmaceutical preparations, medical books ... surgical, dental and veterinary instruments, etc. circa 1857 (Box 10)
  - Parke, Davis & Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Complete catalogue. 1916 (Box 10)
  - Pengelly, R., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - To the ladies of the house (Private) undated, [circular for Zoaphora, a remedy for "female complaints"] (Box 10)
  - Physicians Pharmacal Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue. 1904 (Box 10)
- Exercise--Equipment and Supplies
  - Sanitarium Equipment Co., Battle Creek, Mich
    - How to use the Battle Creek Health Builder 1927 (Box 10)
    - Ride your way to health. 1927 (Box 10)
- Fire-Fighting Equipment
  - American-Marsh Pumps, Battle Creek, Mich
    - Barton U-type front-mounted centrifugal fire pumps. Bulletin 75, ed. no. 4. circa 1938 (Box 10)
    - Barton-American fire pumps, type DM, duplex-multistage midship mounted. Bulletin 8731. circa 1900s (Box 10)
- Food
  - American Spoon Foods, Petoskey, Mich
    - Catalogue. Fall/winter 1995-1996 (Box 10)
    - Catalogue. Spring/summer 1990 (Box 10)
  - Curtis Corporation, Long Beach, Calif
    - Investigation of the ripe olive situation in Detroit. 1921 (Box 10)
  - Diamond Crystal Salt Co., Saint Clair, Mich
    - Preserving vegetables by salting. circa 1940s (Box 10)
    - Salting beets, carrots, corn, green beans, and spinach. circa 1940s (Box 10)
  - Foote & Jenks, Jackson, Mich
    - Extract of lemon. circa 1903 (Box 10)
  - Marvelli Co., Detroit, Mich
    - More than sixty ways to cook Marvelli macaroni. Edited by Sarah Tyson Roper. 1900 (Box 10)
  - Moran, Fitzsimons & Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalog no. 18 March 23, 1888 [groceries and household supplies] (Box 10)
  - Rafal Spice Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Spices, teas, coffees, and food specialties. circa 1988 (Box 10)
  - Zingerman's Delicatessen, Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Catalog of good food. Fall 1993 (Box 10)
    - Catering. 2004 (Box 10)
    - Holiday gift catalog for food lovers December 2005 (Box 10)
    - Mail order catalog. 1996, December 20, 2005 (Box 10)
    - Menu and newsletter. September 1993, December 1993 (Box 10)
    - Wedding cakes. 2004 (Box 10)
    - Zingerman's news. January/February-March/April 1996, May-June, 2005 (Folder NB A613 C357)
    - Zingtrain seminars. June 2004-June 2005 (Box 10)
- Furniture (Box 11)
  - A. J. Phillips Co., Fenton, Mich
    - Phillips' "continental" woodenware (Box 11)
      [Stepladders, ironing boards, clothes racks, hat racks, cutting boards, clothes hangers, hooks, etc.]
  - American Seating Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - 1957, School Furniture (Box 11)
  - Arkitektura Showrooms, Birmingham, Mich
    - [Portfolio] 1980s (Box 11)
  - Berkey & Gay Furniture Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Berkey & Gay Furniture Undated (Volume 1)
  - Berry Brothers, Ltd., Detroit, Mich
    - Natural woods-and how to finish them circa 1899, [Stains and varnishes] (Box 11)
  - Carl Forslund, Inc., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Carl Forslund's portfolio of quaint American. 1954 (Box 11)
  - Cedarcraft Manufacturing Co., Greenbush, Mich
    - Cedarcraft rustic building, furnishing, fencing (Box 11)
  - Charlotte Furniture Co., Charlotte, Mich
    - Reproductions and adaptations of antique furniture for the bedroom and living room circa 1920 (Box 11)
  - E. H. Stafford Co., Muskegon, Mich
    - Standard office appliances and business furniture [catalogue no. 6 circa 1890] (Box 11)
  - Grand Rapids Fancy Furniture Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Catalogue for 1917/1918 [general line, emphasis is on bookcases, desks, and cabinets] (Box 11)
    - The Grand Rapids furniture record. July, 1911 (Box 11)
  - Grand Rapids Show Case Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - The New way line of show cases, interchangeable units, wardrobes... 1922 (Volume 2)
    - Flyer circa 1910s (Box 11)
  - H. E. Shaw Furniture Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Shaw spinets [desks] circa 1920s (Box 11)
  - Herman Miller, Zeeland, Mich
    - Action office: the physical system 1979 (Box 11)
    - C-forms. 1979 (Box 11)
    - Furnishing the interior environment. 1979 (Box 11)
    - Managing the work environment. 1979 (Box 11)
  - Heywood-Wakefield, Menominee, Mich
    - Theatre Seating by Heywood Wakefield. circa 1950s (Box 11)
  - Holland Furniture Co., Holland, Mich
    - Attractive furniture for the bed room. 1918 (Box 11)
  - Ihling Bros. & Everard, Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Office and typewriter desks undated (Box 11)
  - James L. Angle Co, Division of Carrom Industries, Ludington, Mich
    - Furniture catalog circa 1950 (Box 11)
  - John Widdicomb Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Individual furniture. circa 1920s (Box 11)
    - Price list. No. 69 July 12, 1926 (Box 11)
  - Mack & Co., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Catalogue of quaint furniture in arts and crafts [catalogue no. 24 circa 1900] (Box 11)
  - Money-Back Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Undated, leaflet advertising chairs (Box 11)
  - New England Furniture Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Kalendar Katalogue for 1894 [bedroom furniture] (Box 11)
  - Pioneer Rustic Furniture Co., Engadine, Mich
    - Undated, folder advertising rustic chairs & chests (Box 11)
  - Retting Furniture Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Book of Retting [catalogue of furniture] for 1920 (Box 11)
  - Sligh Furniture Co., Holland, Mich
    - Catalogs of office furniture: 1978/79 (Box 11)
    - Catalogue of bedroom furniture for the fall season 1895 (Box 11)
    - Catalogue of bedroom furniture: 1908, 1916, 1928, 1930, 1932, Undated (Volume 3)
    - Catalogue of hotel furniture circa 1909 (Box 11)
    - Price list July 1895 (Box 11)
  - Superior Seating Co., Muskegon, Mich
    - School furniture. circa 1910s (Box 11)
  - Wilhelm Furniture Co., Sturgis, Mich
    - Spencer, Arthur Raymond. Character in furniture. 1924 (Box 11)
  - Baker Furniture Co., Holland and Grand Rapids, Mich (Box 12)
    - A Collection of Baker Furniture assembled for those who appreciate the finest. circa 1967, circa 1968 (Box 12)
    - A Guide to English and French Furniture of the Eighteenth Century. 1940 (Box 12)
    - A New Collection by Baker Furniture...as featured by Interior Design magazine. Undated (Box 12)
    - Furniture and the Connoisseur. Undated (Box 12)
    - Milling Road Furniture...list prices of wood and upholstered. December 1967 (Box 12)
    - Milling Road, a collection of choice European designs... Undated (Box 12)
    - The Baker Book. circa 1970 (Box 12)
    - The Baker Furniture continental collection. 1983 (Box 12)
    - The Normandy Collection...presented editorially by House and Garden magazine. 1967 (Box 12)
    - The Woburn Abbey Collection by Baker. Undated (Box 12)
- Hardware--Building Fittings and General Hardware Goods (Box 13)
  - A. J. Phillips Co., Fenton, Mich
    - Phillips screen goods. Catalog "B": Custom made fly screens.[Screens for doors, windows, hardware, etc.] (Box 13)
  - Dayton Pump and Manufacturing Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Water systems for shallow wells circa 1925 (Box 13)
  - Detroit Blower Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Sirocco service, v. 8, no. 3. circa 1915 (Box 13)
  - Earth Closet Co., Muskegon, Mich
    - Catalogue of Heap's patent dry earth closet, indoor commodes, and sanitary conveniences circa 1888 (Box 13)
  - Hazen Manufacturing Co., Hudson, Mich
    - Hazen pumps, well supplies, etc. Catalog no. 25 Undated (Box 13)
  - Henry Rowe Manufacturing Co., Newaygo, Mich
    - Catalog 40 of wood turnings, rosettes, drawer pulls, wood feet and plugs, etc. circa 1926 (Box 13)
  - James Walker and Son, Detroit, Mich
    - Catalog of brass, iron and copper goods for plumbers, steam fitters, engineers, machinists, and engine builders circa 1889 (Box 13)
  - L.L. Johnson Lumber Manufacturing Co., Charlotte, Mich
    - The straight grain (catalog ed.). 1997 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Gypsum Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Plasterers manual and builders guide. circa 1920s (Box 13)
  - Michigan Seamless Tube Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Annual Report December 31, 1928 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous building fittings and general hardware goods
    - Lathing and Plastering Manual. circa 1928 (Box 13)
      (Published under the auspices of Lathers' Local No. 5, Plasterers' Local No. 16 (Published for 1928 Home Builders Show)
  - Twentieth Century Tile Roofing Co., Rochester, Mich
    - [Leaflet for roofing tile undated, 1 sheet 4 pages folder (Box 13)
- Hardware--Machinery, Engines, and Supplies
  - A C Spark Plug Co., Flint, Mich
    - Spark plugs, marine instruments; tile produced by Flint Faience & Tile Co. of Flint, a subsidiary (Box 13)
  - Automobile Equipment Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Automobile accessories, revised wholesale price list 1916-1917 (Box 13)
  - Automobile Supply Manufacturing Co., Brooklyn, N.Y
    - Newtone motor driven, Handphone mechanical warning signals. Undated (Box 13)
  - Battle Creek Machinery Co., Battle Creek, Mich
    - Boult's carving, paneling, moulding and dovetailing machine circa 1875 (Box 13)
  - Besser Co., Alpena, Mich
    - Quality equipment for the concrete products industry. circa 1980s (Box 13)
  - Borg-Warner Corporation. Ingersoll Kalamazoo Division, Kalamazoo, Mich
    - New ideas for a peaceful tomorrow. circa 1960s (Box 13)
    - The LARC, a new amphibian. circa 1961 (Box 13)
  - Clark Equipment Co., Buchanan, Mich
    - Clark Axles for Motor Trucks. 1920 (Box 13)
    - Complete line of electric/internal combustion industrial trucks and attachments. 1977 (Box 13)
    - Integrated material movement. circa 1960s (Box 13)
    - This is Clark Equipment. circa 1968 (Box 13)
  - Cook's Standard Tool Co., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Standard jacks. 1909 (Box 13)
  - Craftsmen Motor Corp., Chicago, Ill
    - Autocraft-Bovey heater. circa 1917 (Box 13)
  - Edward F. Lyon Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Automobile springs and axle shafts: dealers' confidential price list no. 6. 1916 (Box 13)
  - Ferro Machine & Foundry Co., Cleveland, Ohio
    - Ferro V-type motors. circa 1917 (Box 13)
  - J. P. Gordon Co., Columbus, Ohio
    - Gordon seat covers, tailored to fit. 1917 (Box 13)
  - Kerr Machinery Corporation, Detroit, Mich
    - Deming Oil-rite trademark double-acting power piston pump, fig. 809 circa 1925 (Box 13)
  - Lansing Iron and Engine Works, Lansing, Mich
    - Catalog of general mill supplies [leather and rubber belting, rubber goods, iron pipe, boiler tubes, brass goods, etc.] 1888 (Box 13)
  - M. D. Hubbard Spring Co., Pontiac, Mich
    - [Catalog] 1923 (Box 13)
  - Machinery Company of America, Big Rapids, Mich
    - Saw and knife machinery, catalogue no. 30 Undated (Box 13)
  - Magee Sheet Metal Machinery Co., Ypsilanti, Mich
    - Catalogue No. 7 1949 (Box 13)
  - Monnier Auto Supply Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue. 1909 (Box 13)
  - National-Standard Co., Niles, Mich
    - Standard automobile jacks Undated (Box 13)
  - Perkins & Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Illustrated descriptive catalogue of Willis J. Perkins' improved shingle mill machinery. 1888 (Box 13)
  - Raymond Garage Equipment Co., Adrian, Mich
    - Raymond visible service station. circa 1920s (Box 13)
  - Richfield Iron Works, Flint, Mich
    - [Catalog. 1980s] (Box 13)
  - Riverside Iron Works [Lake Superior Iron Works Houghton Mich.] Detroit, Mich.
    - Catalogue of gearing, wheel ... steam engines, mining and other machinery circa 1877 (Box 13)
  - Timken-Detroit Axle Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Handbook of motor vehicles used by the United States Armed Forces. 1944 (Box 13)
  - Willis Shaw Machinery, Chicago, Ill
    - Some bargains in used machinery. December 1905 (Box 13)
  - Wm. B. Mershon & Co., Saginaw, Mich
    - Mershon band sawing machinery. circa 1925 (Box 13)
  - Wolverine Motor Works, Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Catalog of 3-cylinder 4-cycle gasoline marine engines circa 1905 (Box 13)
    - Catalog of gasoline marine engines circa 1902 (Box 13)
- Hardware--Tools and Machine Tools (Box 14)
  - American Logging Tool Co., Evart, Mich
    - Manufacturers of logging tools and appliances and logging tool handles. circa 1910s (Box 14)
  - Chas. A. Strelinger and Co., Detroit, Mich
    - A book of tools, being a catalogue of tools, supplies, machinery, and similar goods. 1895 (Box 14)
    - A book of tools, being a catalogue of tools, supplies, machinery, and similar goods. 3rd ed. 1895 (Box 14)
    - Discount sheet for A book of tools. 1895 (Box 14)
    - Price lists of machinists tools made by Brown & Sharpe Mfg. Co. Catalogue no. 107. 1905 (Box 14)
    - Tools and tool chests. 1895 (Box 14)
    - Wood workers' tools, being a catalogue of tools, supplies, machinery, and similar goods. 1897 (Box 14)
    - Woodworkers' tools, supplies and light machinery. circa 1885 (Box 14)
  - Fulton Iron and Engine Works, Detroit, Mich
    - Illustrated catalog of the Detroit tools. circa 1889 (Box 14)
  - Wilmarth and Morman Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Catalogue for the "New Yankee" drill grinder circa 1903 (Box 14)
- House Furnishings
  - Alabastine Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Alabastine book [wall coverings] circa 1920 (Box 14)
  - Cobbs & Mitchell, Inc., Cadillac, Mich
    - Michigan's woods intelligently exploited ... undated (Box 14)
      [Cover title: 'Michigan's woods in use.' Uses of lumber in buildings and room furnishings]
  - Detroit Furniture Shops, Detroit, Mich
    - Suggestions for better homes. February 1925 (Box 14)
    - [Furniture catalog combining decorating suggestions.] (Box 14)
  - Dishmaster Corporation, Pontiac, Mich
    - [Flyer for the Manville dishmaster dish washing device circa 1950s (Box 14)
  - Mack & Co., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Real sensible gifts. [Christmas catalog. Furniture. circa 1930 (Folder NB A613 C357)
  - Miscellaneous house furnishing companies
    - Stylist; a magazine for the home [Winter] circa December 1916-January 1917 (Box 14)
  - Stensrud, Herman, Model Plumbing and Heating Establishment, Marquette, Mich
    - To my friends and customers 1913 (Box 14)
      [Bathroom interiors; also has views of various departments of the business]
  - White-Steel Sanitary Furniture Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - White-Steel bathroom cabinets (Box 14)
- Jewelry
  - Sidney Krandall and Sons, Jewelers, Troy, Mich
    - Generations 1978 (Box 14)
      [Includes a history of the Co.]
- Lighting
  - Superior Manufacturing Co., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Ann Arbor incandescent gasoline lamps. circa 1905 (Box 14)
    - Ann Arbor incandescent lamps and lighting systems circa 1904 (Box 14)
- Livestock
  - Blissveldt Farms, Jenison, Mich
    - Complete dispersal, 85 registered Holstein cattle 1935 (Box 14)
      [annotated with selling prices and buyers' names]
  - Burdick, W. M., Chesaning, Mich
    - Stud card for the trotting bred stallion "Tiff Jerome" Undated (Box 14)
  - Chronometer Stock Farm, Paw Paw, Mich
    - Catalogue of trotting stock circa 1893 (Box 14)
  - Crapo, W. W., Flint, Mich
    - Catalogs of second and third public sales of pure bred Hereford cattle 1888 (Box 14)
    - Catalogue of Grassmoor herd of pure bred Hereford cattle circa 1887 (Box 14)
  - Hillsdale Breeding Stables, Hillsdale, Mich
    - Catalogue of standard bred trotting stallions circa 1892 (Box 14)
    - Catalogue of standard bred trotting stallions circa 1983 (Box 14)
  - Sunny Side Stock Farm (John Den Bleyker), Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Holstein Friesians circa 1885 (Box 14)
    - Supplementary catalog circa 1887 (Box 14)
  - West Michigan Holstein Breeders' Association
    - Catalog of the annual October guarantee quality consignment sale. 1919 (Box 14)
- Medical Supplies
  - Chrystal, Andrew, Marshall, Mich
    - Professor Chrystal's electric belts and appliances. circa 1899 (Box 14)
- Musical Instruments and Accessories (Box 15)
  - Castiglione Accordion Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Castiglione presents the top lines of accordions. circa 1968 (Box 15)
    - [Brochure], Spring 1957 (Box 15)
  - Grinnell Bros., Detroit, Mich
    - Our Christmas annual. 1902 (Volume 4)
  - Heritage Guitar, Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Suggested retail price list. January 1994 (Box 15)
    - [Catalog. 1993] (Box 15)
  - Jerome H. Remick & Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Latest catalog. circa 1921 (Box 15)
    - Marches, waltzes, songs and dances. Catalog no. 15. circa 1908 (Box 15)
    - Marches, waltzes, songs, dances. Catalog no. 21. circa 1914 (Box 15)
  - Shar Products, Ann Arbor, Mich
    - [Catalog] Spring 1994 (Box 15)
- Office Equipment and Supplies
  - Business Men's Paper Press Co., Wayland, Mich
    - Business men's paper press. circa 1910s (Box 15)
  - Doubleday Brothers & Co., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Township and village books and forms. 1938 (Box 15)
  - Ihling Bros. & Everard, Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Books, blanks and supplies ... Catalogue no. 50. circa 1901 (Box 15)
  - Macey-Wernicke Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Macey filing cabinets, catalogue no. 4404. circa 1890s (Box 15)
  - Shaw-Walker Co., Muskegon, Mich
    - Multi-cabinet systems. circa 1890s (Box 15)
      [2 different catalogs]
    - Shaw-Walker systems. 1905 (Box 15)
    - [Loose advertising material] (Box 15)
  - Wagemaker Furniture Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Catalogue no. 3, containing modern and improved filing cabinets, sectional & solid, sectional bookcases, filing systems & card index record systems. 1904 (Box 15)
    - Catalogue no. 5, filing cabinets sectional and solid, sectional bookcases, vertical filing systems and card index record systems (Box 15)
- Paint
  - Acme White Lead and Color Works, Detroit, Mich
    - Acme quality house paint (new era). circa 1900s (Box 15)
    - Acme quality painting guide book. 10th ed. 1916 (Box 15)
    - Specifications for finishing ... circa 1920s (Box 15)
  - Berry Brothers, Ltd., Detroit, Mich
    - Descriptive list of varnishes & japans circa 1910 (Box 15)
- Printing--Specimens
  - Scharf Tag Label and Box Co., Ypsilanti, Mich
    - The information contained in this little brochure is of value to you Undated (Box 15)
- Refrigerators
  - Kelvinator Sales Corporation, Detroit, Mich
    - Cooking with cold. 1932. (Box 15)
      [Refrigerators, plus cook book]
- Road Machinery
  - Moore Specialty Manufacturing Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Moore patent snow plow. circa 1910, [horse-drawn snow plow] (Box 15)
  - Thompson Smith's Sons, Cheboygan, Mich
    - Cheboygan snow plow and road maker. circa 1905 (Box 15)
- Scientific Apparatus and Instruments
  - Eberbach & Son Co., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - A priced list to accompany Shepard's Elements of chemistry.[2nd ed. undated] (Box 15)
    - Catalog PY Physiological apparatus [instruments used for physics classes] 1921 (Box 15)
    - Catalogue PY Physiological apparatus [instruments used for physics experiments] circa 1915 (Box 15)
    - Physical apparatus catalogue [instruments used for physics classes] after 1913, 2 copies (Box 15)
      (1 copy with later additions tipped in)
- Sewing Machines and Accessories
  - Domestic Sewing Machine Co. [agent: Timis Marshall, Mich.], New York, N. Y.
    - Folder advertising "domestic sewing machines" circa 1872 (Box 15)
- Sleighs and Sledges
  - Kalamazoo Wagon Co., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Cutter catalog 1899-1900 (Box 15)
  - Thorpe Carriage Co., Jackson, Mich
    - Color folder advertising cutter sleighs. circa 1880 (Box 15)
- Sporting Goods
  - Baker Economy Furnace Co., Camden, Mich
    - Catalogue of hot-air furnaces circa 1905 (Box 15)
  - Marble Safety Axe Co. [Marble Arms & Manufacturing Co.], Gladstone, Mich
    - Catalog of axes, knives, and guns circa 1911 (Box 15)
    - Catalog: Marble's Outing Equipment. 1948, 1955 (Box 15)
    - Catalogs of specialities for sportsmen [axes, knives, guns, etc.] 1905, 1908/09 (Box 15)
  - Osgood, N. S., Battle Creek, Mich
    - Catalogue of portable folding canvas boats circa 1880 (Box 15)
  - Shakespeare, William, Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Catalog of fishing reels circa 1902 (Box 15)
- Stoves and Heating Equipment (Box 16)
  - Brewster, E. E., Holly, Mich
    - Broadside advertising lamp chimney stove and Brewster's electric battery (patent medicine) circa 1887 (Box 16)
  - Bulkley, H. G., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Bulkley's Steam Dry Kiln. 1857 (Box 16)
  - Detroit Steam Radiator Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Two pictures of radiators (Box 16)
  - Detroit Stove Co., Detroit, Mich
    - 1903, Deluxe catalog and price list of Jewel Stoves and ranges [352p] (Box 16)
    - 1930, Catalog No. 136 B-G [Jewel gas ranges] (Box 16)
    - 1930, Catalog No. 136 [Jewel gas ranges] (Box 16)
    - 1931, Catalog No. 137 B-G [Jewel gas ranges] (Box 16)
    - 1931, Catalog No. 137 [Jewel gas ranges] (Box 16)
    - 1931, -Folded leaflet advertising Jewel gas ranges (Box 16)
  - Detroit Vapor Stove Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Red star Detroit vapor oil stove: 25th annual dealers catalog. 1919 (Box 16)
  - Dudley and Holmes, Detroit, Mich
    - Circular advertising "Boynton's Patent Air Warming and ventilating furnace." [July, 1855] (Box 16)
  - East Saginaw Gas Co., East Saginaw, Mich
    - Two advertisements for the Eclipse Gas Range 1891, 1892 (Box 16)
  - Glazier Stove Co., Chelsea, Mich
    - Catalog of stoves, ovens, cooking units, etc. circa 1900 (Box 16)
  - Grand Rapids Welding Supply Co., Grand Rapids, Mich